Hello.
The next thing we're going to do is make it so that this health ball will accurately show throughout
health.
Our skeleton character has.
If we go back to our scans and beep, I will also create a new variable and just call it max health.
Then I'm going to go to where we set up and then we can play and then we can play.
We're going to set our max health variable to be whatever our health is.
You're going to see why we're doing this in just a second.
So just hook this up here and here and then click compile.
Next, if we go back to our new health bar.
We want to go over to the graph and we can just delete event pick an event pre construct.
We're going to be working with this event construct and the way this will work.
As soon as our health bar is shown on the screen, it's going to fire this node.
So event construct we'll drag in our progress bar and set this one get progress bar and we just want
to drag up that full set percent.
Next, I'm going to create a new variable I just call a skeleton reference.
And under variable type, I will need to look for the skeleton or whatever you call a skeleton character.
So I called my skeleton beep.
So once you find it just like object reference, then I want you to drag in your scans and reference.
Look for that skeleton reference and just drag up here and forget else.
And then drag.
Okay.
Again.
And forget Max health.
Now, if I go back to my designer, all progress bar can only go from a value of 0 to 1.
So here it is.
This bar can only go from a value of 0 to 1.
So we need to make sure our health fits between this value.
So the reason I just made the max health, whatever our health is, is because if, for example, I
made my skin tone half health or fiber, what we can do is health divide by whatever it max health is,
and that will give us a value between zero and one.
So if we just drag off here and look forward divide.
And hook us up here.
And then just connect us to here and talk about being constructive here.
This will now put our health between a value of zero and one and accurately display it on our health
bar.
There's one more thing we need to do.
Whenever our enemy will be attacked, we're going to need to update our health bar.
So just right click and look for add custom event and just call this update Health bar.
Then just hook this up here.
The next thing we're going to do is make it so that we can visually see our health war whenever our
enemy is attacked.
So if I go into a scan to beep.
And go to the viewport.
Let's go add and look for widget.
Once you select it, I want you to go to widget class and select the enemy health path that we just
made.
So you should be able to see your health well.
I want you to just rotate this.
Then move it up above your character.
Then under space, I only just select screen.
So I'm going to explain what we've just done.
If I set this to be world, that means we're only be able to see our health bar when it's in the world.
However, if I set this to be screen, that means we're going to see our health bar no matter where
we are on our screen.
And when I damage my enemy, I want to always see the health bar.
So just set this to be screen.
Next, if you remember inside of our Enemy Health bar, we made a reference to our skeleton reference.
We need to make sure that our health bar can accurately cool this reference.
In order to do that.
If we go back to our scans and beep and head over to that graph.
I'm just going to delete this as it's in the way.
On November can play.
We're going to track in our widget and to struggle and we'll get widget.
This will allow us to just drag up here and toss to our enemy Alpha.
I'm going to wrap this up here, and then from here we can set the account in reference so we can look
at set scan to ref.
And if we just drag up here for self.
We'll set the Scantron raff to be whatever the Scantron is.
So I'll just pick this up here and go compile.
So I go play.
We'll see our health ball and our game.
It's actually kind of big, so I'm going to make it a bit smaller.
And my designer.
So you can just adjust the size here.
I'm gonna make it about 200 by 40.
So I think that size is good.
Next.
If I go play, we can see my enemy's health.
Although I don't always see my enemies helper, I only want to see it when I'm damaging my enemy.
So in order to set that up, if I go back to my skeleton and back to the viewport.
If we select our widget, go to details and look for visibility.
Then under visible.
Just make sure that this is unchecked.
This will make sure that the health bar is hidden.
Next, if we go back to the main graph.
We also just need to right click on this as enemy helper and root it to a variable.
That way we can just reference this later.
Then if we go over to where we set up the damage.
Whenever we damage our enemy, I am just going to drag in my widget and look for set visibility.
And I'm going to hook this up here and just leave this checked and that will make it to my health.
Ball is visible next in order to make my health better.
Update whenever my enemy is damaged.
After I damage my enemy, I'm going to drag in my health by reference.
And called the Update Health Custom event.
So I'm just going to move this back.
And connect the node here.
Then when my enemy dies, I'm going to hide the health bar again from a copy.
This.
And then I'm going to paste this here.
Although this time a manila unchecked.
And just go compile and save.
So now am I go play.
And I go up to my knee.
You can't see the health bar.
If I attack it, we can see the health bar.
And we can see that it's gone a bit.
If I continue attacking my enemy, the health bar should decline.
So I think I gave my enemy like, ten health.
So that's why it has quite a lot to speed this up.
So my enemies nurse lost health.
If I hit it, the health boss would disappear and the enemy should die.
So I do it.
Then he dies and the help disappears.
So with that, we set up a health bar for our enemy, and I think that just looks a bit better.